Michael Kithinji

FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER

Gmail Github LinkedIn Twitter Medium Portfolio

SUMMARY

Full-stack software developer with 3 years of hands-on experience in developing web applications. Looking to obtain a Frontend Engineer position where I will be able to use my UI design, debugging, deploying, maintenance, and performance control JavaScript skills. Proficient with JavaScript, jquery, React, Redux, HTML, CSS, Tailwind CSS, Bootstrap, and Ruby on Rails.

SKILLS

Front-End: JavaScript, React, Redux, jQuery, HTML5, CSS3

Back-End: Ruby, Rails, MySQL

Tools & Methods: Git, GitHub, Heroku, Netlify, Mobile/Responsive Development, RSpec, TDD,

Chrome Dev Tools

Professional: Remote Pair-Programming, Teamwork, Mentoring

EXPERIENCE

HIGHLIGHTED PERSONAL PROJECTS Remote

Full Stack Web Development Student & Mentor 01, 2023 - Present

Mastered intermediate and advanced topics in full-stack development (including Rails, Git, and DS&A challenges) while building multiple full-stack projects both independently and via pair-programming.

<u>TodoList</u> — Easy, free, and simple-to-use project that may be used to schedule your daily activities.

Built with: (HTML, CSS, JavaScript APIs)

<u>JavaScript Bootcamp</u> — This is a JavaScript bootcamp capstone project. The project is responsive to mobile devices.

Built with: (HTML, CSS, JavaScript, APIs)

<u>Portfolio</u> — This is my portfolio; This project was built Using React, and it is mobile responsive

• Built with: (React)

MICROVERSE

Remote

Mentor (Volunteer) 01, 2023 - present

• Mentoring junior web developers, providing technical support through code reviews.

- Proposing improvements to code organization to improve code quality and overall performance.
- Providing advice and tips on how to maintain motivation to maintain longevity in the program.

UNITED STATE OF AFRICA Nairobi, Kenya

BACKEND NODE.JS ENGINEER 01, 2022 – 12, 2022

- "Provided advice and tips on how to maintain longevity in the program."
- "Mentored junior web developers, providing technical support through code reviews."

EDUCATION

MICROVERSE 01, 2023 - present

Remote Full Stack Web Development Program, Full Time

- Spending 1300+ hours mastering algorithms, data structures, and full-stack development while simultaneously developing projects with Ruby, Rails, JavaScript, React, and Redux.
- Developing skills in remote pair-programming using GitHub, industry-standard gitflow, and daily standups to communicate and collaborate with international remote developers.

CHUKA UNIVERSITY

Degree, Concentration 09, 2017 – 12, 2021

• "Bachelor of Arts in Economics and Mathematics."